<resources>
    <string name="app_name">DynamicFitness</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="arm_description">Working out the arms heavily during upper-body exercises. All types of pull-up and rowing motions will sufficiently work the elbow flexors, and all types of push-up and dipping motions will sufficiently work the elbow extensors. For this reason, every time you train your chest, shoulders, and back you\'ll necessarily be working your arms. The involvement of the arn musculature during multijoint movements is particularly important from a bodyweight training perspective. It\'s easy to isolate the arm muscles when using free weights or cables. Simply grab a weighted implement and flex or extend the elbows. Things become more complicated, however, when trying to use your body as a barbell It\'s difficult to manipulate the body around the elbow joints. This isn\'t to say that it\'s not a good idea to try to target the arms with single-joint movements. But it is critical to understand that multijoint movements are the most productive in terms of total muscular output. When performing arm exercises, concentrate on squeezing the intended muscles and don\'t allow other muscles to do the job. Before heavy sets of elbow flexion exercises, Arnold Schwarzenegger used to envision his biceps growing as big as mountains. Focus on feeling the arm muscles contracting in order to create the desired movement. Bodybuilders call this a mindmuscle connection, and it takes time to sufficiently develop these neuromuscular pathways. Training for sport and functional purposes is more about training movements; whereas training for physique and aesthetic purposes is more about training muscles. For this reason, think about arm training as contracting your muscles against resistance. This will help you put maximal stress on the intended muscles. Although the forearms are indeed part of the arms, they will be worked during gripping movements, including pull-ups and rowing motions, while training the back musculature.</string>
    <string name="shoulders_description">The deltoids are important stabilizers of the glenohumeral joint and need to be strong and coordinated for rapid movement and for the prevention of shoulder dislocations. The deltoids contain three heads, each having a different function. When you get lean enough, you\'ll be able to see the three heads contracting while you train. A well-developed middle head, or lateral deltoid, is the subdivision of the delts that leads to the illusion of the wide X shape mentioned earlier. The anterior head is on the front of the body, and posterior head is located on the back of the body. The anterior head is worked during push-up variations because it is a strong shoulder flexor and transverse, or horizontal, adductor. (Adduction moves a limb toward the midline of the body, and abduction moves a limb away from the midline of the body.) The posterior head is worked during various rowing and pull-up exercises because it acts as a shoulder extensor and transverse, or horizontal, abductor. However, this head is often underdeveloped. Specific attention to the rear delts is usually provided through transverse abduction movements of the shoulder. While all three heads contribute to handstand push-up movements, the anterior and lateral heads are worked the most during this category of lifts. The posterior head keeps the shoulder stable and contributes slightly to the overall motion. Even if you were never to target your deltoids, you could achieve pretty good development by performing horizontal pressing and pulling movements such as push-ups and inverted rows. But to take your delt development to the next level, it is imperative to work them directly. There seemed to be fewer shoulder injuries many years ago when overhead pressing was more popular thanhorizontal pressing. This practice led to more stable shoulder muscles and balanced strength levels. It should come as no surprise that the deltoids are heavily involved in sporting movements. They\'re involved in throwing jabs and crosses in boxing, chest passes in basketball, and pushing an opponent forward or stiff arming an opponent in American football. In fact, the shoulders are heavily involved in all throwing, swinging, and striking motions predominant in sports such as baseball, tennis, racquetball, swimming, volleyball, and martial arts. The posterior deltoid is highly involved in the backhand stroke in tennis, a spinning backfist strike in mixed martial arts, rowing, or even a Frisbee serve. When carrying heavy loads at the sides of the body, the deltoids contract forcefully to keep the loads away from the body and prevent the humerus, the upper-arm bone, from pulling out of its socket. </string>
    <string name="chest_description">For maximal pectoral development, a variety of chest exercises are warranted because certain exercises are better suited to developing the upper, middle, or lower regions. It may be possible to develop the inner and outer pectoral regions as well; however, research has failed to confirm this. Women who seek defined pecs should focus on upper-pectoral development because this area is more visible on a woman\'s body than the middle or lower pecs. Many men develop adequate middle and lower pectorals through frequent bench pressing and push-upperformance and should focus on upper pectoral development for balanced aesthetics. While the push-up, referred to as a press-up in some countries, is arguably the most popular bodyweight exercise and certainly the most common bodyweight chest exercise, it\'s important to progress to more challenging variations of the exercise for continued results. There are dozens of types of push-ups, and I have included the most effective push-up variations to allow you to achieve your goals. Moreover, it\'s critical that you learn the proper way to perform a push-up from the get-go because a vast majority of exercisers perform this movement incorrectly. I distinctly remember when I started performing push-ups. I was 15 years old and could barely manage three sets of six repetitions. I\'m pretty sure my form wasn\'t up to par back then either. Fortunately, I stuck with it and didn\'t give up. Fast forward to today, I\'m now able to perform 60 nonstop push-ups. A nice fringe benefit of push-up performance is the core stability that comes along with it. The pectorals also are involved in many sport actions. Pushing opponents forward as in American football or sumo wrestling relies heavily on the pees. Straight punching as in ajab or right cross involves the pecs, as does arced punching such as hooks or uppercuts. Tennis, volleyball, racquetball, and handball actions involving overhead and swinging motions across the body such as serving, forehand strokes, and spiking, involve the pectorals, as do throwing motions in baseball and American football. A shotputter and discus thrower require strong and powerful pectorals to heave their implements the maximum distance. Mixed martial arts relies on the pecs for striking, clinching, takedowns, and grappling. Gymnasts and swimmers require strong pectorals for various maneuvers and strokes. Even track and field athletes train the pecs because a strong upper body can increase speed. Some strength coaches prefer various types of push-up exercises to barbell bench pressing because they feel it\'s a safer and morenatural movement pattern. Many feel that the requirements of the scapular stabilizers during the movement creates strong and healthy shoulders and safeguards against injury. The push-up is also a military training staple. Gymnasts are often able to perform a bench press with twice their body weight despite the fact that they never bench press; their extremely strong upper bodies are developed through frequent push-up and dip exercises and gruelling event practice. For optimal sport performance training, explosive pressing exercises are easy to perform through push-up movements that lend themselves to clapping and plyometric (repeated explosive movements) variations</string>
    <string name="core_description">The spine and pelvis work in combination to carry out movement. The lumbar spine can flex, extend, flex to either side, and rotate, while the pelvis can tilt to the front, back, and side and can rotate. And let\'s not forget the hips, which can flex, extend, abduct (move leg away from the middle), adduct (bring leg toward the middle), and internally and externally rotate. These actions require different muscle contributions to carry out the tasks. As you can imagine, many muscles are involved to varying degrees in the various joint actions of the core during activity. In sports, the core is highly involved in nearly every movement. Force is transferred between the lower body and upper body through the core, so the core muscles must modulate their stiffness and timing in order to maximize the transfer of energy from one segment to the next. A weak core is not able to controlexcessive movement, which allows energy to leak instead of transferring it from one segment to the next. The spine and pelvis move to various degrees during sporting movement. For example, during the stance phase of running when the body passes over the supporting foot, the lumbar spine typically extends while the pelvis tilts forward. During rotary actions such as swinging a bat, the front hip internally rotates while the back hip externally rotates, and the external oblique on one side and internal oblique on the other side contract to assist this rotation through a stiff core. Ample motion at the hips and thoracic spine (upper back) limit the amount of rotation in the low back while transferring energy from the hips to the upper extremities. The lumbar spine (low back) must be strong enough to resist being extended during collision sports such as football and rugby. The core is highly involved in all major sporting movements that happen when your feet are primarily on the ground, such as sprinting, jumping, twisting, throwing, and cutting from side to side. It is also involved in other sporting movements, such as swimming. Strong core muscles play a role in posture, as well. In particular, the erectors must be strong to prevent thoracic kyphosis (hunchback), and the abdominals must be strong enough to prevent lumbar lordosis (swayback) and excessive anterior pelvic tilt. Maintaining a balanced core strength helps the body properly distribute forces during heavy and explosive movement, which spares the spine and prevents low back pain. </string>
    <string name="back_description">The back muscles are involved in nearly every sport action. The spinal erectors are the primary muscles for holding the body in an athletic position, which resembles the positioning of a bent-over row exercise. The spinal erectors are also critical in lifting sports such as powerlifting. Olympic weightlifting, and strongman and in rowing and mixed martial arts. The lats are highly involved in rowing, in addition to gymnastics, swimming, and rock climbing. During sprinting, the opposing pairs of lats and glutes work together to transfer force and keep the body balanced. This diagonal pattern from right lat to left glute and left lat to right glute has been referred to as the serape effect by some fitnessexperts, because of the wrapping action around the body similar to a serape. Furthermore, the lats are heavily involved in throwing, serving, and spiking actions. The traps and rhomboids stabilize the scapula during many athletic motions involving dynamic movement of the upper extremities. On a personal note, I have not been dealt good genetics for developing impressive back width. Although my back is very thick from many years of deadlifting, I can\'t achieve the coveted outward flare to my lats no matter how many pull-ups and pulldowns I perform. This is not due to lack of strength either; I\'m able to perform chin-ups with an extra 100 pounds (45 kg) attached to a hip belt, and I\'m able to deadlift well over 500 pounds (227 kg). An impressive lat flare gives the illusion of a narrower midsection and helps produce an athletic looking physique, so unfortunately, I\'ll never appear as aesthetically pleasing as someone with ideal genetics. That said, I have improved my upper-back width considerably through consistent, scientifically based training. I believe that it\'s wiser to perform only a couple sets of a variety of back exercises than crank out four or more sets of just one or two back exercises. The back contains a lot of muscles and you want maximal development of each muscle to function your best. A variety of back exercises ensures that you leave no stone unturned and dedicate adequate attention to the numerous components of the back musculature. In chapter 2, I mentioned that your forearms gain strength through the pulling movements. As you progress in pulling strength, your grip will receive a powerful training stimulus. You won\'t find many people with advanced pull-up and inverted row strength who possess inferior forearm musculature. Get strong and gain endurance through the back exercises listed in this chapter and your entire forearms, both anterior and posterior musculature, will become denser and more muscular.</string>
    <string name="leg_description">The thigh muscles are heavily involved in sports and functional movement. The quadriceps might be the most important muscles in vertical jumping, and they\'re critical for running, cutting, landing, and decelerating as well. The hamstrings might be the most important muscles in sprint running. In weight training, the quadriceps contribute considerably to the squat exercise and the hamstrings contribute considerably to the deadlift exercise. I will be unable to name every sport action that requires ample leg strength and power; there are simply too many to mention. Every ground sport that requires speed. power, and agility relies predominantly on the leg muscles, and even swimming, rowing, and climbing uses combined hip and knee extension for propulsion. Because the hamstrings cross both the knee and hip joints, they play critical roles in transferring power from the knee joint to the hip joint during explosive movement. Considering that most sports are performed one leg at a time, it makes sense to include plenty of single-leg lower-body exercises in your routine. Single-leg exercises develop sensorimotor (balance) skills while simultaneously improving strength and power. Many athletes are considered quad dominant because their quadriceps overpower their hamstrings. Athletes with overpowered quadriceps in relation to the hamstrings typically fail to move ideally when jumping, running, landing, and cutting, thereby predisposing themselves to injury. For this reason it\'s important to develop strong hamstrings. Possessing strong quadriceps is important for sports, but you should also possess strong hamstrings as both hip extensors and knee flexors. Kneeflexion exercises work more on the distal part of the hamstrings (the part closer to the knees), while hip-extension exercises work more on the proximal part of the hamstrings (the part closer to the hips). This chapter includes a variety of hamstring exercises so you can strengthen them through all of their roles and through full ranges of motion, leaVing you with no weaknesses. </string>

</resources>
